# 我觉得他这种烹调技法
This is a very traditional cooking technique.
# 它非常传统
# 收汁
Condense the sauce.
# 色泽枣红 口味酸甜
This dish has sweet and sour flavour pork ribs with maroon glazing.
# 糖醋排骨
Sweet and sour pork ribs
# 糖醋排骨谁都做哪儿都做
Sweet & sour pork rib is a beloved dish in China.
# 哪个菜系也做
Each Chinese local cuisine has its own unique cooking technique.
# 做上海的 还是做宁波的
Which style should we follow? Shanghai cuisine or Ningbo
# 还是做山东的 还是做四川的呢
Maybe Shandong cuisine, or how about Sichuan cuisine?
# 我这个知识面比较窄
I have limited scope of knowledge in this area.
# 然后我这么多年是用
What I normally do in these years is braising pork ribs with sugar and vinegar.
# 糖和醋焖出来的
# 冯氏的其实就 家常版
Feng style is actually the home style.
# 剩下这头干嘛用
What should we do with meat scraps?
# 这是您喜欢吃的脆骨
It’s your jam. Gristle.
# 留出来我给您腌好了做蒜香骨
I saved them on purpose so I can marinade them and make deep-fried pork cartilage with garlic for you.
# 我给你讲一事儿
Tell you what
# 带这个小脆骨的做糖醋也好吃
Our dish will be delicious even if you keep the gristle.
# 这段就是做糖醋排骨最好的
This part is the most suitable ingredients for our dish.
# 一刀俩 口儿大一点吧
Chop into two. A bigger chop
# 过瘾 今天咱们不要细 要味儿
Magnificent! We don’t need fancy work today, we need tasty and mixture flavour.
# 那就一破为二了啊
I’ll chop them into two pieces.
# 咱们把排骨搁这儿
Put ribs aside.
# 用水给它浸泡一下
Soak them in water.
# 泡个半个小时就行
For half an hour or so.
# 把里边有血水的给它往外拔一拔
This process will draw out some blood from the meat.
# 然后这个工夫咱们准备点料
We can prepare other ingredients while we are waiting.
# 葱段一点要选葱白
White part of scallion.
# 它做烧菜比较出味
It adds more flavour into our dish.
# 然后还不容易破型
And they don't break down.
# 然后咱们就直接切成段就行了
Chop them into pieces
# 跟排骨这么长就可以了
Similar length as pork ribs
# 反正有这三段就够了
Three pieces are enough.
# 一定要整一点这料
We need the aromatics to be chunky
# 因为待会咱们料要挑出来的
As we're gonna pick them out later.
# 我们专业叫吃其味不见其物
We have a saying in our profession. Seasonings and aromatics should be tasted but not (physically) found in the dish.
# 姜大一点
More gingers please.
# 还有黄冰糖 大料瓣
Add some brown rock sugar, star anise
# 蒜呢 蒜在这儿
Where is garlic? Here is it!
# 我当你说做糖醋不放蒜  吓我一跳
Gosh, I thought you were gonna skip the garlic. No way!
# 然后蒜也不用太多了一破两半吧
We don’t need too many garlic, just cut the cloves in to halves.
# 你们做些东西尽量
When you are producing this dish,
# 我主张你们不要去拍
I suggest that you don't smash the garlic,
# 一定要用刀切
but chop it.
# 刀切不损害它汁儿
Chopping will keep the garlic juice
# 然后做出菜来显得干净
And the presentation is much cleaner.
# 我倒了一碗醋 米醋
I poured one bowl of vinegar, rice vinegar.
# 米醋和糖的比例是多少
what’s the ratio between sugar and vinegar?
# 糖是三 醋是二
3 part sugar and 2 part vinegar
# 甜压酸 稍微偏甜一点
We need more sugar, as sugar can neutralize the sour flavour.
# 半个小时以后这排骨还真白了
Ribs turn lighter colour after half an hour indeed.
# 排骨洗完了底口来一勺盐
Wash and clean the ribs. Sprinkle some salt.
# 五克盐 给它抓一下
5g salt. Massage the ribs.
# 咱们这儿腌的时候就不搁
We don’t need to put this now.
# 待会儿咱们烧的时候
Later when we start braising ribs,
# 我得需要您一点黄油来借它的味
I need to add some cooking wine (Shaoxing wine)
# 弄两块钱的 五毛钱就行
- Use the 2RMB one
- The 0.5 RMB one is enough
# 这个盐抓一下起什么作用师弟
Why do we need to massage the ribs with salt?
# 让它基本的入味 要有底口
Add some basic flavour into them.
# 师父我跟我讲盐是定味的
My master told me salt can set up basic flavour to meat.
# 先把盐入进排骨里头
Meat absorbs salt,
# 把味给它定住 定海神针
saltiness is locked into the ribs
# 好这油温开始陆续地升起来
alright. The oil is heating up.
# 现在这里边有一个关键
Now, there is a key step.
# 八角 你看这就是秘方
Star anise is our secret ingredient.
# 因为我岳父最爱吃糖醋排骨
This is my father-in-law’s favourite dish.
# 把岳父搬出来了
So, you start using your father-in-law as a shield.
(So you quoted your father-in-law)
# 我平常给他家里边做的时候
I cook this dish in exactly the same way
# 就是这么做的
as I cook for my father-in-law.
# 待会大料跟排骨跟猪肉特别配
Star anise and pork ribs are a power couple.
# 然后烧出来肉的香味特别浓
This is dish is going to have a rich aroma later on.
# 吹吧反正我和小魏待会儿也得尝
Stop bragging, Xiao Wei and I will try it.
# 待会儿您尝一下就知道了
Be my guest and help yourselves.
# 其实做好一道菜 这就是细节
Truth be told, it's the details that determine whether a dish is successful
# 对 得学会
Agreed.
# 好大料味基本上就出来了
Smells of star anise is spreading out.
# 搁一个排骨咱试试
Put one rib in.
# 油温低 稍微有点低
The temperature is a little bit low.
# 我是属于非专业 非专业选手
I am a non-professional player.
# 只能在家里边还能行做菜真不灵
Merely a home cook
# 老冯从事餐饮也将近二十年了
Lao Feng has been running his restaurant business for nearly 20 years now.
# 因为炸这排骨一定要注意观察
We need to pay attention to the ribs.
# 外边能起一层焦焦的皮就可以了
It is ready when there is a layer of brown crust on the rib.
# 咱先放在这锅里
Just leave the ribs here.
# 这油温还是有点低
The oil temperature is still a bit low.
# 油温你知道什么时候下么我告诉你
Do you know when is the best time to put in the ribs?
# 稍微冒有烟的时候
When the oil is almost smoking
# 油温上烟的时候合适
The suitable timing is when there is smoke on top of the oil.
# 一下抱住水分锁定
Hot oil helps lock the moisture inside the meat.
# 如果你要像这种温度下去
If the meat was deep fried in low oil temperature,
# 它就成熬了 成浸了
It becomes a stew in the oil.
# 它水分锁不住
Meat juice can’t be locked in.
# 再烧一会
Keeping heating up.
# 因为你不是为了给它炸熟
The purpose of deep-frying is not to fully cook the meat
# 你为了锁住（水分）定型
but to set the shape and lock meat juicy inside.
# 可以下了 没问题这是这感觉
It’s ready to deep-fry now. No worries.
# 看见没有 这才叫炸
See? This is deep-fried ribs.
# 这温度将近有二百
The temperature is nearly 200 degrees.
# 不要扒拉它 漂起来就出锅
Don’t stir them, just wait until they float.
# 看这大料的颜色
Look at the colour of this star anise.
# 基本上这油温是可以的
The temperature is good.
# 冯爷说了看看大料的颜色
Sir Feng said take a look at the colour of the star anise.
# 好嘞 这排骨就可以了
Great! Done.
# 这颜色好看 非常好
The colour is fantastic and beautiful. Amazing.
# 层次感很强是吧
And different layers.
# 三叔得为老冯服务
San Shu should serve Lao Feng.
# 三叔这手劲还是可以的
San Shu has very good strength.
# 咱们这锅 就就着这个锅
And then, with the work...
# 然后咱们炝一下锅
And then, we need to stir-fry the ribs,
# 来点底油 有点像炒糖的感觉
Add some cooking oil, it seems like stir-frying sugar.
# 油太多了 我再盛出一点油
Too much oil, let me take some oil out.
# 油还是多 没事他有他的玩法
Still too much, but no worries, he has tricks.
# 咱还学学 各家有各家的高招
Time to learn. Different chef, different techniques.
# 一定要留出来点 二次加糖
Keep some of them aside, and add sugar again.
# 待会咱们调味用 小火炒糖
These are for seasoning later on. Fry the sugar over low heat.
# 这糖可千万别炒过了
Don't overcook it.
# 不能跟咱们炒糖色是的
It’s not like normal caramel.
# 就要它糖色的金黄色
We need to cook the sugar until it's amber not brown.
# 这个炒法不加水么师弟
Does this method require water, Shi Di (a way to call junior fellow apprentice in Chinese)?
# 我是从来不加的
Never for me.
# 他是油炒法
He makes caramel with oil.
# 有水炒 有混合油水炒 有油炒
Different methods: caramel with water, with oil and with both.
# 三种炒法
There are three ways.
# 其实这也是糖醋排骨的关键点
This is another key point.
# 这糖还不能炒过了
Caramel should be just right,
# 很要火候 过了成糖色了
we need to focus on the temperature, otherwise it’ll be overcooked.
# 这个排骨肯定好吃师叔
These ribs must be delicious Uncle.
# 你知道为什么
Do you know why?
# 我觉得这种烹调技法 非常传统
I think this cooking method is very traditional.
# 他等于是炒完糖色以后
After the caramel is ready,
# 用糖跟醋去焖 焖酥了这种排骨
ribs will be braised with sugar and vinegar.
# 所以这个人要小心 他给咱俩埋雷呢
We'd better keep on the right side of him, his words mean more than what he says.
# 我是一个非专业 我没有刚强牛
I am not professional. Gang Qiang is better.
# 其实我师弟干的全都是专业的活
Actually my Shi Di does all the professional work.
# 看这个糖就是金黄色就可以了
Ok, it turns into gold colour now.
# 你要炒嫩一点也可以
If you want, you don’t need to cook them completely,
# 因为你后边翻锅的时候它还在变色
Because it will continue to cook and change colour when you stir-fry the ribs later.
# 颜色漂亮  这个是最关键的
Beautiful colour. This is the key point.
# 然后把蒜也放进去
Add all garlic in.
# 糖醋排骨离不开蒜
Sweet-sour pork ribs and garlic match perfectly.
# 它把蒜的香味抱进去
Pork ribs will absorb the garlic flavour.
# 这时候蒜的香味出来了
Now the garlicky flavor is brought out.
# 然后再放姜
Add in some ginger.
# 姜是去腥 提香 增加肉的香味
Ginger can remove meat odor, and enhance the aroma
# 你看姜和蒜的香味混合到一起
Ginger and garlic are now mixed up.
# 一定要这三个要分出层次来
Layers of flavours are important.
# 这颜色多漂亮是吧
Fantastic colour.
# 葱段 先煸炒 要有耐心
Spring onion. Stir-fry the spring onion, be patient.
# 因为这个 你看最后咱收汁的时候
We are going to reduce the sauce at the end.
# 要收到 跟这个汁儿一样
The final consistency should look exactly like this.
# 叫怎么进锅 怎么出锅
We call it, "It goes out of the wok in the same way it went in"
# 这葱味也出来了
I can smell spring onion now.
# 真好 真好真好
Nice, very nice.
# 这时候最关键的一步 这个醋
The most important step, vinegar.
# 烹下去 整个儿倒
Pour it in.
# 火稍微小点
Turn the heat down a little bit.
# 要是说大火一烹 糖醋味就出来了
Sweet and sour flavour tends to be amplified by high heat.
# 这个小亮子跟谁学的啊
Where did you learn it?
# 跟三叔学的
From San shu.
# 咱们点点盐 这盐千万不要多
Sprinkle a little bit salt.
# 因为咱们有底口了
As we have massaged the ribs before with salt.
# 酱油有一点就行
A little bit soy sauce.
# 就要它这味儿 借味
We just want to have some soy sauce flavour.
# 这时候把这糖再放进去 二次加糖
And now, this is the second time we add in sugar.
# 网友们看见没有
Does everyone see how we did it?
# 二次加糖是调糖和醋的味儿
Adding sugar again is to flavour the dish and balance the sweetness and sourness.
# 还加水吗 我就要用您一点黄酒
Do you need more water? I need some yellow rice wine.
# 现在咱们的排骨 猪肉都挺嫩
Ribs are very tender and soft.
# 基本这收汁收完了 它也就熟了
It will be ready to serve once the sauce is reduced enough.
# 如果糖醋排骨要晾凉了 更好吃
It would taste more delicious if you let it cool first.
# 这一步要把三叔的黄酒
This step is to use San Shu’s yellow rice wine.
# 给它做一下稀释
To dilute.
# 但是我做糖醋排骨我爱用镇江醋
But I love Zhenjiang Vinegar for sweet and sour ribs.
# 镇江香醋
Zhenjiang Vinegar.
# 然后给它搁进去
Add it in.
# 今天咱们家没有  就这凑活了
We don’t have Zhenjiang vinegar at home. Just deal with it.
# 米醋也挺好吃
Rice vinegar is tasty as well.
# 这个盖必须得要盖上来
Lid on.
# 咱把火调的小一点 先入味后收汁
Lower the heat. Let the flavor penetrate the meat first before reducing the sauce.
# 咱们现在有十五分钟
After 15 mins,
# 然后咱们开大火 开始收汁
Heat up to reduce the sauce now.
# 把所有的料头取出来 出品漂亮
Remove garlic, ginger and other aromatics. We need fancy presentation.
# 最起码讲究点 这葱也好吃
Agree with fancy presentation. And spring onion tastes good.
# 这个糖还得再跟一点 差不多了
More sugar. Nice.
# 三次调味
This is the third time.
# 这回的醋香就全出来了
And now the aroma of vinegar is spreading out completely.
# 这是烹 有醋香味
This called fry. With the smell of the vinegar
# 咱们就这么大火
This is the highest heat we can get.
# 没办法就这么大火
There's nothing else we can do
# 这个已经行了 你看这汁
It’s ready. Take a look at the sauce.
# 没问题了
No problem.
# 这汁挂得非常均匀 传统手法
Beautiful sauce, authentic technique.
# 炒糖的时候一定不要炒过了
Do not overcook the caramel.
# 这是最关键的
This is the key point.
# 色泽枣红 口味酸甜
Maroon glaze, sweet and sour flavour.
# 好了 这汁正合适
Bravo, just perfect.
# 小柠檬配的合理 酸甜适度
Garnish with lime wedges for acidity
# 得嘞 太漂亮了 齐活
Beautiful. Nice and magnificent!
# 糖醋排骨
Sweet and Sour pork ribs
# 真脆 漂亮漂亮
Very crispy and very fancy presentation.
# 你看又是先手机吃饭
Camera eats first
# 好漂亮
Amazing.
# 我先来一块排骨 来一口菜
I need to have on rib first and then some veggie.
# 甜酸甘香 吃的利落
Sweet, Sour, rich flavour.
# import ending.srt 00:09:32,000